CONTACT ME AT

∨kastanenka@gmail.com

+1 519-215-1033

in @vkastanenka

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Honours Bachelor of Science

Specialist in Microbiology

and Microtechnology

Sep 2013 - Jun 2018

DEVELOPER SKILLS

Git / Github

5 Semantic HTML5

∃ CSS3 / Frameworks

TS JavaScript ES6+ / Typescript

🥸 React / Frameworks

Redux / Redux Toolkit Query

Content Management Systems

Node.js / Express

MongoDB / Mongoose

Cy Cypress / Jest

Command line / npm

■ Analytics

† Accessibility

≗ SEO

Figma

REFERENCES

Valerie Carruthers
 Manager
 valerieamelia.c@gmail.com
 +1 289-385-3577

Lulysses Pabuna
Staff Developer, Front-End
upabuna@gmail.com
+1 647-588-9231

Daniel Bedoya
Front-End Developer I

db09012001@gmail.com
+57 319-256-3720

VICTORIA KASTANENKA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Adaptable software engineer with a proven history of developing high quality products in both individual and collaborative environments. Managed the KOHO Financial Inc. marketing web repository, transforming a disparate collection of pages into a consistent, performant, and accessible web experience. Eager for a position with unique problem solving opportunities to learn new skills and further development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer II

KOHO Financial Inc.

Toronto, ON | January 2022 - January 2024

- Refactored the marketing website's Github repository and Sanity CMS into a component based website builder, enabling non-developers to create, update, and preview page layouts in half the time of code-based previews.
- Assisted in developing the second version of the company's admin platform. Responsibilities
 included converting Angular to React 18 with Redux Toolkit Query, updating API routes,
 improving User Success workflow, designing dashboards in Figma, and providing continued
 support for product updates. Decreased customer inquiry response time by over 6 hours.
- Combined LaunchDarkly feature management and Amplitude funnel analysis platforms, enabling marketing to A/B test new website content, leading to increased efficiency and data-driven results in product onboarding.
- Improved the marketing website's SEO by auditing the website sitemap, expanding crawlable content, and refining sitewide metadata. Resulted in higher site traffic and Google site ranking.
- Interviewed, trained and managed new hires and co-op students to work with the marketing web ecosystem, allowing the team to expand the scope and size of their initiatives.
- Organized a Kanban system with management to provide an efficient workflow between development and non-development teams. Provided visibility between different team initiatives and ensured consistency in developer priorities.

Front-End Developer I

KOHO Financial Inc.

Toronto, ON | August 2020 - December 2021

- Led a performance audit and refactor of marketing web repository. Changes included code splitting and lazy loading imported packages, updating the mobile experience to a lightweight version of desktop, and standardizing asset formats. Improved Google Lighthouse score from mid 20s to high 80s.
- Collaborated with EqualWeb Accessibility Solutions to audit and update sitewide accessibility as well as introduce their Accessibility Widget. Resulted in ADA and WCAG compliance for web repositories while offering extended accessibility options for users with specific needs.
- Managed analytics for product onboarding flow. Responsibilities included adding pixels for platforms such as Google Analytics, TikTok, Facebook, and Twitter/X, setting up and tracking analytics events, and creating analytics funnels.
- Coordinated with marketing designers to create, update, and deploy pages for the marketing website that were performant, accessible, and responsive. Involved reviewing designs, formatting assets, and choosing external packages to provide additional site functionality.
- Developed and implemented schemas sitewide for marketing's Sanity CMS. Provided non-developers methods to manage content sitewide while adding additional functionality such as page and language variants.